<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
 
 <!-- Experiments: LF -->
      
    <string-array name="lf_devices_array">
        <item>Power Extension</item>
        <item>Driller</item>
        <item>Lightning</item>
        <item>Devices with Transformers</item>
        <item>Other...</item>
    </string-array>   
    
    <string-array name="exp_lf_more_info_1">
    	<item>4</item>
    	<item>8</item>
    	<item>3</item>
    	<item>4</item>
    	<item>2</item>
    </string-array>
    
    <string-array name="exp_lf_more_info_2">
    	<item>32</item>
    	<item>31</item>
    	<item>33</item>
    	<item>32</item>    	
    	<item>28</item>
    </string-array>  
    
    <string-array name="exp_lf_instructions">
        <item>
		Electric power-sockets generate electromagnetic fields. Turn a power-bar on and measure the field by approaching the sensor (the antenna) as close as possible to the power-socket (do not put the antenna in the hole, this would destroy the device!!). The sensed field is magnetic with a low-frequency (50 Hz).\n
		- Now try to back-off some centimeters.\n
		- When does it stop sensing anything?.\n
		- Try connecting a device with a transformer (e.g., a laptop) to the power-bar, what do you notice?\n
		- What happens if you turn the switch of the power-bar off?\n
        </item>
        
        <item>
        Because of the size of its motor, a driller generates a relatively important magnetic field.\n
		- Turn a driller on and use it in the air.\n
		- Back-off progressively from the sensor.\n
		- When does the sensor stop measuring a field?\n
		- Why do you think that despite of its importance, the field generated by a driller is not truly dangerous?
        </item>
        
        <item>
        Lamps generate magnetic fields but some light-bulbs more than other.\n
		- Prepare a number of different light-bulbs (e.g., economic, LED, incandescent) and plug them.\n
		- Which light-bulb generates the biggest field? Why?\n
		- Try reaching a fluorescent light-bulb (e.g., on the celling of an office), what you you notice?\n
        </item>
        
        <item>
        Devices with a transformer generate magnetic fields.
		- Plug a WiFi router in.\n
		- What do notice?\n
		- Now, unplug the small, round power-socket at the device end. What do you observe?\n
		- Repeat these steps with other devices with transformers.
        
        </item>
    </string-array>
    
    <string-array name="exp_lf_conclusions">
    	<item>
    	"Better turn our power-extensions off! This allows us to save energy and minimizes the risks. Moving power-extensions connected to devices a least 1 meter away from places where you stay long hours (e.g., your bed) is also a good idea since at this distance, the magnetic field is almost null."
    	</item>
    	
    	<item>
    	"The bigger the motor, the stronger the generated magnetic field is. However, since we are usually exposed to these fields for very short periods, they are harmless. Hence, duration of exposure to a field is a very important variable when evaluating the risks."
    	</item>
    	
    	<item>
		"Light-bulbs generate rather low magnetic fields. However, economic bulbs and fluorescent tubes generate stronger fields. Thus, it is a good idea to stay a few meters away (~2m) from these lamps."
    	</item>
    	
    	<item>
    	"Transformers generate magnetic fields as soon as they are plugged-in (and consume power!) and this even if the device they are attached to is not turned on! The strength of these fields depends on the transformer's size. Hence, it makes sense to unplug transformers when they are not in use (or connected them to a switch that can be turned off). This is especially important in places where we spend long hours, such as bedrooms."
    	</item>
    </string-array>
   
<!-- Experiments: HF -->     
        
   <string-array name="hf_devices_array">
        <item>Cordless Phone (DECT)</item>
        <item>WiFi Router</item>
        <item>Mobile phone</item>
        <item>Other...</item>
    </string-array>
    
    <string-array name="exp_hf_more_info_1">
    	<item>5</item>
    	<item>7</item>
    	<item>7</item>
    	<item>2</item>
    </string-array>
    
    <string-array name="exp_hf_more_info_2">
    	<item>53</item>
    	<item>54</item>
    	<item>39-45</item>
    	<item>52-55</item>
    </string-array>  
    
    <string-array name="exp_hf_instructions">
        <item>
		"Plug a cordless phone (DECT) in.\n
		- What do you notice?\n
		- Wait for about one minute, what do you observe?\n
		- Walk a few meters away, 10 meters away, move to another room.\n
		- What did you observe?"
        </item>
        <item>
		"Plug the WiFi router in.\n
		- What do you notice? How about after 30 seconds?\n
		- Move to the room next door and then outside. What do you notice?\n
		- Up to what distance can you observe the field?\n
		- Move the orientation of the router's antenna, do you notice any changes?"
        </item>
        <item>
		"Find a working mobile phone.\n
		- Turn the phone on and call a friend.\n
		- Move away from the sensor while calling.\n
		- What do you observe? Put the phone very close to the sensor and then ~30 cm away (the distance of a hands-free kit).\n
		- Compare your observations. Try also comparing several mobile phones.\n
		- Try sending a SMS or downloading data (make sure you have a data plan!).\n
		- Try setting your phone to \"flight-mode\". What do you observe?"
        </item>
        
    </string-array>

   
    <string-array name="exp_hf_conclusions">
        <item>
    	"Cordless phones generate high-frequency fields (1880-1900 MHz). The DECT standard used for many of these phones is designed in such a way that the base-station constantly transmits a signal and thus generates a field (and uses power!) 24-7 which can be measured up to about 100-300 meters. Hence, such devices should not be placed close to bedrooms, beds, sofas and desks and should be shutdown at night. A good alternative is to opt for an ECO-DECT device (or ECO+) which ensures that the device only transmits while in use."
        </item>   
		<item>
        "WiFi routers generate high-frequency electromagnetic fields (2.4 - 5.7 GHz). To signal their presence to devices that can connect through WiFi, they transmit a signal several times per second even when no device is connected. Hence, it is better not to place the routers nearby bedrooms. It is also wise to turn them off at night since they are useless. Another good measure (both in terms of costs, consumption and exposure) is to share routers amongst several neighbors."
        </item>
        <item>
        "Mobile phones generate high-frequency magnetic fields (e.g., GSM 1800 MHz, 3G: 2100 MHz). Compared to other devices, mobile phones are powerful since the antenna they communicate with might be up to a few kilometers away (e.g., the emission of a mobile phone is about ~10x more powerful than a DECT). Moreover, without a hands-free kit, we hold mobile phones real close to our head. Finally, little is known about the effects of mobile phones besides the (harmless) effects of heating. To be on the safe side it is hence wise to respect a few simples rules:\n
		1) Pick a device with a low SAR value. The lower the SAR value, the lower the amount of energy absorbed by body.\n
		2) Use a hands-free kit whenever you can (this makes a significant difference!).\n
		3) Avoid calling while in a car or train: in these cases your phone emits at full power since you are in a metallic structure and your phone constantly changes the antenna it talks to.\n
		4) Try using SMS since their transmission lasts only one to two seconds!\n
		5) Put your phone in flight mode when you don't use it (e.g., at night), since even when not in use, your phone communicates with the antenna regularly. Likewise, in a train or car put it in flight mode if you don't use it since your phone communicates constantly with antennas while moving."
        </item>
    </string-array>
    
    <string-array name="frequencies_array">
        <item>Low-frequency (&lt;30 kHz)</item>
        <item>High-frequency (&gt;30 kHz)</item>
    </string-array>
    
<!-- Tutorials -->
    
    <string-array name="tutorials">
        <item>Electromagnetism and Electrosmog</item>
        <item>Electromagnetic Frequencies</item>
        <item>Risks and Impact</item>
        <item>Prevention</item>
    </string-array>
    
	<string-array name="tutorial_fields_and_smog">
	</string-array>

</resources>
