<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="lang_warning">Please select either English, Français or Deutsch.</string>
    <string name="button_settings">Change language...</string>
    <string name="app_name">Ondes Visibles!</string>
    <string name="device_picker_activity_name">Pick a device...</string>
    <string name="chart_activity_title">Measurements</string>
    <string name="field_selection_title">Pick a Frequency...</string>
    <string name="info_activity_title">Did you know?</string>
    <string name="experiment_activity_title_instructions">Instructions</string>
    <string name="experiment_activity_title_conclusion">Conclusions</string>
    <string name="show_experiment">instructions</string>
    <string name="show_experiment_conclusion">conclusions</string>
    <string name="show_more_info">more info</string>
    <string name="home">home</string>
    <string name="start_experiment">start</string>
    <string name="stop_experiment">stop</string>
    <string name="vibrator">vibration</string>
    <string name="lf_human_readable">low-frequency</string>
    <string name="hf_human_readable">high-frequency</string>
    <string name="field">Electromagnetic field</string>
    <string name="activate_sensor">Activating sensor</string>
    <string name="no_device_selected_lf">This mode lets you freely experiment with the low-frequency sensor.</string>
    <string name="no_device_selected_hf">This mode lets you freely experiment with the high-frequency sensor.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_picker_title">Tutorials</string>
    <string name="toggle_debug">Simulation Mode</string>
    <string name="simulation_on">Simulation enabled!</string>
    <string name="simulation_off">Simulation disabled!</string>
    <string name="toggle_log">Logger</string>
    <string name="log_on">Logger enabled!</string>
    <string name="log_off">Logger disabled!</string>
    <string name="more_info_title">In the brochures...</string>
    <string name="more_info_description">For more info please look at page</string>
    <string name="more_info_description_device">For more info about this device please look at page</string>
    <string name="more_info_flyer_1">of brochure 1 (l\'électrosmog au quotidien) et</string>
    <string name="more_info_flyer_2">of brochure 2 (l\'électrosmog dans l\'environment).</string>
    
    
    <string name="tut_1_title">Electrosmog</string>
    <string name="tut_1_a_text">
    "In order to better understand what an electromagnetic field (EMF) is, let's look at what's happening with a TV."
    </string>
    <string name="tut_1_b_text">
    "When the TV is not plugged in there is no field."
    </string>
    <string name="tut_1_c_text">
    "When you plug the TV in (without turing it on), an electric field appears. If we were talking about light and not electricity, this field could be represented by the zone it lights up. Hence, a field is a zone of influence. A bit like light, an electric field does not traverse easily all materials. Hence, it is easy to isolate ourselves from the influence of such a field (e.g., using walls, cellings, metal, etc.)"afonds, métal, etc.)."
    </string>
    <string name="tut_1_d_text">
    "When turning the TV on, a new field appears: the magnetic field. Unlike the electric field, this one goes through pretty much anything and thus, it is harder for us to isolate ourself from its influence."
    </string>
    <string name="tut_1_e_text">
    "However, two laws are valid for both types of fields:\n1) The strength of a field depends on the tension (in volts) and on the applied current (in amps). Thus, the lower the emitting power, the lower the field is (the darker the sky it :-)).\n2) Fields\' strength lowers with the distance. As a consequence the further you stand from the device, the weaker is the field. Once again, a bit like the sun, the further away you are the colder/darker it gets."</string>
    <string name="tut_1_f_text">
    "Last but not least, this is the electromagnetic field generated by a hair-dryer (source: BAFU). What we call electrosmog are the fields generated by devices of our daily life. Our devices (TVs, hair-dryers, WiFi routers, plugs, mobile phones, etc.) but also devices from the infrastructure (cell antennas, power-lines, etc.)."
    </string>
    <string name="tut_1_more_info_1">2</string>
 	<string name="tut_1_more_info_2">4</string>
    
    <string name="tut_2_title">Fréquences</string>
    <string name="tut_2_a_text">
    "Electromagnetic fields switch their phase (+/-) and intensity on a regular basis. We say that they oscillate with at a given frequency. This frequency is measured in Hertz. 1 Hz represents a cycle per second. We categorize fields into two groups: low-frequency and high-frequency fields depending on the time they take to oscillate." 
    </string>
    <string name="tut_2_b_text">
    "Low-frequency fields are fields which cycle is below 30'000 oscillations/second (&lt;30 kHz). In this range we find rail-ways, power-lines and many of our electric devices."
    </string>
    <string name="tut_2_c_text">
	"High-frequency fields are those with more than 30'000 oscillations/second (&gt;30 kHz). High-frequencies are used mostly to transport data (that is encodes through the oscillations). As an example we use them for TV/radio transmission, mobile phones (Bluetooth 2.4GHz, GSM 1.8GHz, 3G/UMTS 2.1GHz, etc.), for WiFi communication (2.4 GHz) but also for microwaves ovens (2.4 GHz). A these frequencies, both the electro and the magnetic fields travel together. This is why we talk about electromagnetic fields!"
    </string>
    <string name="tut_2_d_text">
    "Above high-frequencies we find waves oscillating extremely rapidly, such as visible light. Above light, we find ionizing waves. This means that they can change atoms and molecules). As an examples, x-rays or the radioactive gamma-rays can modify matter which makes them so dangerous."
    </string> 
    <string name="tut_2_more_info_1">2</string>
 	<string name="tut_2_more_info_2">4-5</string>
 	
    <string name="tut_3_title">Risks and Effects</string>
    <string name="tut_3_a_text">
    "The human body is a conductor which means that electric and magnetic fields can generate currents in our body."
    </string>   
    <string name="tut_3_b_text">
    "At a low frequency, electric fields do not reach far through our skin (except when the contact is direct, e.g., having the very bad idea of putting your finger in the power socket!!!). Nevertheless, magnetic fields can penetrate our organism. When the intensity is high enough, this can irritate our nerves, muscles (e.g., our heart!). However, such intensities do not appear in our daily life thanks to limit values defined by the government."
    </string>    
    <string name="tut_3_c_text">
    "For weaker intensities of low-frequency fields, the question is more complex. While contradicted by others, specialists have found evidences of a number of effects when the exposure time is very long or permanent (e.g., when living close to a high-power transmission line). Amongst these effects, researchers have observed mood modifications and effects on our hormones production. An increasing risk of leukemia amongst children was also observed. However, researchers lack certainty on these effects."
    </string>
    <string name="tut_3_d_text">
    "For high frequency fields, the only proven effect is a heat increase. This can be observed when using a microwave since we use a 2.4 GHz field to heat up our food. This frequency is similar to the one used in European mobile phones but the power of a mobile transmitter is 500 times weaker (and a mobile phone does not usually operate in a metallic cage). After using a mobile phone against your ear for 30 minutes, a heating spot with an increase of 0.4 degrees Celsius can be observed. This could, for instance, explain light headaches. However, in Europe, limits are set by the governments to protect us from the effects of heating."
    </string>
    <string name="tut_3_e_text">
	"Except for heating no effect of high-frequencies we are exposed to on a daily basis is universally accepted. However, a number of researchers think that there are other effects such as a modification of our sleep, cells, DNA or a higher risk of cancers. Other studies systematically contradict these results. This shows that the possible consequences reach beyond our current understanding. We can't prove the effects but can't completely deny them either!"
    </string>
    <string name="tut_3_more_info_1">13-14</string>
 	<string name="tut_3_more_info_2">12-13</string>
    
    <string name="tut_4_title">Prévention</string>
    <string name="tut_4_a_text">
    "Because we potentially do not yet understand all risks of electromagnetic fields, a good approach is to avoid what can be avoided! A number of simple actions can reduce our exposure. As a consequences, these actions significantly reduce the risks as most specialists agree on one point: the duration and intensity of exposure matters a lot!"
    </string>
    <string name="tut_4_b_text">
    "Unplug and turn off! Most of our devices do not need to be permanently plugged in or turned on. Turning them off helps us save energy and reduces our exposure. Also try to avoid stand-by modes often electromagnetic fields persist. This is also valid for extension cables, let's unplug them if they are not in use! Similarly, most of the mobile phones have a flight mode that makes sure the phone is not connected to any wireless network anymore."
    </string>
    <string name="tut_4_c_text">
    "Keep your distance! Electromagnetic fields weaken significantly with the distance hence, just moving away from devices and extension cords is a good idea. In the case of mobile phones, using a hands-free kit does make a difference as it moves your head away from the device and thus lowers direct exposure!"
    </string>
    <string name="tut_4_d_text">
    "Not in my bed! Since we spend a great amount of time in our sleeping-rooms, we should avoid filling them with electromagnetic fields. No TV, WiFi router, cordless phone in you sleeping-room. Mobile phone should be set to flight mode and electronic alarm clock as well as devices and extension cables should be located at least two meters away from your bed." 
    </string>
    <string name="tut_4_e_text">
    "Now that we understand the basics of electromagnetic fields and their risks, we are ready to experiment! Through these experiences, concrete actions will be proposed to reduce your exposure to each individual device. Let's make the waves visible, les ondes visibles! (click on the last button to go to the experiments)."
    </string>
    <string name="tut_4_more_info_1">15</string>
 	<string name="tut_4_more_info_2">29-30</string>

	<string name="about_activity_title">Credits and acknowlegements</string>
	<string name="about">
	Ondes Visibles! Version 1.0\n\n
	Hardware:\nJean-Pierre Guinard, Dominique Guinard\n\n
	Software:\nDominique Guinard\n\n
	Concept:\nRobert Unteregger, Dominique Guinard\n\n
	Graphics: dryicons.com/freeicons\n\n
	Sources:\nmobile-research.ethz.ch, OFEV, serveral reports and papers.\n\n
	This is a collaboration between Cudrefin02 and ETH Zurich (webofthings.org)\n\n
	</string>
</resources>
